questions = [
    {"Question": "Who founded the Judaic religion?",
     "Choices": ["Abraham", "Adam", "Jesus"],
     "Answer": "Abraham",
     "Explanation": "He is the patriarch of the religion. Abraham is the founding father of the original Hebrew "
                    "religion of Judaism, which started in Judah."},
    {"Question": "Who is the Messiah?", "Choices": ["Abraham", "Elijah", "Moses", "Jesus"], "Answer": "Jesus", "Explanation": "Jesus is known as the Messiah, or anointed one, who delivers the sinful ones from their sin."},
    {"Question": "Who was king when Jesus was born?", "Choices": ["Solomon", "Herod", "Saul"], "Answer": "Herod", "Explanation": "Herod the Great was king when Jesus was born. He wanted to kill Jesus."},
    {"Question": "Who hated the disciples but experienced conversion on the way to Damascus?", "Choices": ["Judas", "Saul", "John"], "Answer": "Saul", "Explanation": "Saul of Tarsus saw to the killing of many believers, including the first martyr, Stephen. While traveling to Damascus, he was met by a heavenly being most people believe was Jesus. The encounter resulted in Saul becoming a believer and an apostle. Saul's name was changed to Paul."},
    {"Question": "Who brought gold, myrrh, and frankincense to young Jesus?", "Choices": ["Shepherds", "Priests", "Magi"], "Answer": "Magi", "Explanation": "An unknown number of wise and educated men, known as the Magi, came to visit Jesus sometime after his birth. A star in the east guided them. They brought three expensive gifts. Tradition assumes that if there were 3 gifts, there must have been 3 Magi. The Bible does not specify how many magi came."},
    {"Question": "Who built a giant boat called the Ark?", "Choices": ["Adam", "Noah", "Moses"], "Answer": "Noah", "Explanation": "Noah received instructions to construct a massive boat. The purpose was to save humanity and the animal world from the destruction of the world that was coming in a massive flood."},
    {"Question": "How many people were on the Ark?", "Choices": ["Two", "Four", "Eight"], "Answer": "Eight", "Explanation": "Eight people were on the Ark. Noah, his wife, his three sons, and their wives were on the Ark."},
    {"Question": "Who did God transport to Nineveh using a big fish?", "Choices": ["Jonah", "Daniel", "David"], "Answer": "Jonah", "Explanation": "God commanded Jonah to go to Nineveh to deliver a message. Jonah tried to run away. God dispatched a large fish to carry Jonah. The trip took 3 days. The fish spit Jonah out on the beach near Nineveh."},
    {"Question": "Who entered the lion's den?", "Choices": ["Jonah", "Daniel", "David"], "Answer": "Daniel", "Explanation": "Daniel was forced into a lion's den at the command of King Darius, the Mede. Darius was tricked into giving the order by his jealous underlings."},
    {"Question": "Which prophet did God take up to heaven in a fiery chariot?", "Choices": ["Enoch", "Moses", "Elijah"], "Answer": "Elijah", "Explanation": "Elijah did not die. Something resembling a fiery chariot transported Elijah directly to heaven. Elisha was with him at the time and assumed Elijah's ministry."},
    {"Question": "What did God give Moses when he was on Mount Sinai?", "Choices": ["A staff with a serpent's head", "The Ten Commandments", "The Beatitudes"], "Answer": "The Ten Commandments", "Explanation": "Moses received two stone tablets during the 40 days he was with God. They contained the original Ten Commandments. God himself engraved them with his finger."},
    {"Question": "How many sets of the commandments did God make for Moses?", "Choices": ["One", "Two", "Three"], "Answer": "Two", "Explanation": "Moses brought down the first set of tablets, and upon his arrival at the camp, he witnessed the Israelites having a party, and they were worshiping a golden calf idol. Moses was so angry that he threw the commandments to the ground and broke them into pieces. Moses had to trek back up the mountain to ask God to create a second set of tablets."},
    {"Question": "How did Aaron explain to Moses about how and why the golden calf was made?",
     "Choices": ["An angel came and told us to make a golden idol.", "The devil showed up and forced us to make a golden calf.", "There was this fire, and the people threw some gold into it, and out came this calf."],
     "Answer": "There was this fire, and the people threw some gold into it, and out came this calf.",
     "Explanation": "People threw some gold into it, and out came this calf. Really! Exodus 32:24"},
    {"Question": "Who looked backed at Gomorrah and turned into a pillar of salt?",
     "Choices": ["Eve", "Ruth", "Lot's wife"],
     "Answer": "Lot's wife",
     "Explanation": "Lot's wife disobeyed God. She looked back at Gomorrah as it was being destroyed by God."},
    {"Question": "Who slew 1,000 Philistines with a single blow to the jawbone?",
     "Choices": ["David. He faced the Philistines during a battle.", "Samson, after the Israelites gave him to the Philistines.", "Stephen, who was a disciple, before he was attacked by the Philistines when they came to stone him."],
     "Answer": "Samson, after the Israelites gave him to the Philistines.",
     "Explanation": "Samson killed 1,000 Philistines out of revenge for them killing his wife."},
    {"Question": "Whose brothers sold him into slavery?",
     "Choices": ["Esau", "Joseph", "Benjamin"],
     "Answer": "Joseph",
     "Explanation": "His jealous brothers sold Joseph into slavery to an Egyptian guard named Potiphar. They were jealous of a coat that their father had given Joseph. Joseph became a powerful leader in Egypt, serving directly under the Pharaoh."},
    {"Question": "Who used a sling and smooth stone to kill a giant?",
     "Choices": ["Samson", "Daniel", "David"],
     "Answer": "David",
     "Explanation": "David went to the battlefront when he was a young shepherd to take food and drink. While there, he heard the blasphemous shouting of the Philistine giant Goliath. David decided to answer the giant's challenge. He attacked the giant with a sling and a smooth stone. After David slayed Goliath, David chopped the giant's head off with the giant's sword."},
    {"Question": "Who betrayed Jesus to the religious mob on the night of His arrest?",
     "Choices": ["Simon", "Thomas", "Judas Iscariot"],
     "Answer": "Judas Iscariot",
     "Explanation": "As Jesus predicted at the Last Supper, Judas Iscariot betrayed Jesus. Judas identified Jesus with a kiss when the religious mob came to the Garden of Gethsemane to arrest him."},
    {"Question": "What happened to Judas Iscariot after the mob took Jesus away?",
     "Choices": ["He fled to Egypt.", "He committed suicide.", "The disciples slew him."],
     "Answer": "He committed suicide.",
     "Explanation": "The Bible says his guts spewed out."},
    {"Question": "What was King Daniel's first occupation?",
     "Choices": ["Prophet of God", "Captain of the guard", "Shepherd for his father"],
     "Answer": "Shepherd for his father"},
    {"Question": "Who denied knowing Jesus three times on the night of Jesus' arrest?",
     "Choices": ["Paul", "Peter", "Judas"],
     "Answer": "Peter",
     "Explanation": "Even though Peter said he would never deny Jesus, he did so on the night of Jesus' arrest. At the Last Supper, Jesus predicted Peter would deny him three times before the cock crowed in the morning."},
    {"Question": "Who watched as Moses floated among the reeds along the riverbank?",
     "Choices": ["The mother of Moses", "The brother of Moses", "The sister of Moses"],
     "Answer": "The sister of Moses",
     "Explanation": "Moses' mother hid him for three months. Fearing for his life, she put Moses into a basket and placed it on the river. She hoped that the royal court would find Moses and spare his life. Moses' sister, Miriam, followed along the riverbank. Pharaoh's daughter found and adopted Moses. Pharaoh's daughter, without knowing, hired Moses' biological mother as his nursemaid. Pharaoh's court and family did not know that the nursemaid was the biological mother."},
]

